[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: Yanming |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Welcome to Getting Started with Music Theory.
欢迎来到音乐理论入门。
My name is Bruce Taggart.
我的名字是Bruce Taggart。
I teach music theory in the College of Music at Michigan State University.
我在密歇根州立大学音乐学院教授音乐理论课程。
This class is for
这门课程受用对象是
anyone who is interested in starting to learn the technical side of music.
任何对于有兴趣开始学习音乐技巧的人。
Maybe you play guitar and wonder how chords work and why some chords sound good
有可能你弹吉他， 好奇和弦是如何产生效果的， 为什么有些和弦效果很棒，
and some chords sound bad when you're harmonizing a melody.
有些和弦的效果却很糟糕， 当你在搭配一段旋律的时候。
Maybe you'd like to arrange songs for
或许你想编曲
a vocal group you sing in or a band you play in.
为一个你参与的合唱团或者乐队
Maybe you're interested in composing, this course is a good place to start.
或许你对作曲很感兴趣， 这门课程是一个很棒的开始。
Although, it helps to be able to read music, and know something about scales and
虽然，已经具备识谱能力、和阶与和弦的相关知识会更有益，
chords, it's not required.
但不是必需的。
I'll start with basic melody, basic harmony and basic musical notation.
我会从基础的旋律、和声和乐谱开始讲起。
By the end of the course we'll be reading music in bass and treble clefs, notating
这门课结束时，我们会认识低音谱号和高音谱号，
rhythms in duple and triple meters, and talking about triads and seventh chords,
分辨二拍子、三拍子节奏，以及谈论三和弦与七和弦
notating them and labeling them using several different chord notation systems.
并用一些不同的和弦标记系统来标记它们。
The course is mostly about western tonal music, that is,
这个课程基本上是关于西方调式音乐
the musical language that started around 600 years ago in Europe
——这是一种在欧洲超过六百年的音乐语言，
growing into our classical popular and jazz music of today.
现在成长于我们的古典、流行和爵士音乐。
We'll look at nuts and bolts of tonal music.
我们将了解调式音乐的具体知识。
What makes it tonal?
是什么让音乐有音调？
How do the individual notes combined into melodies, chords and harmonies?
如何把一个个音符组合起来，变成旋律、和弦，以及和声？
How do rhythm and meter organize music in time?
如何把节奏和节拍准确组合在一起？
How do we write it all down?
我们要如何写下来？
And what special terminology and labels we can use to explain it all?
以及我们可以用什么特殊的术语和标签来解释这一切？
That, after all, is what music theory is really all about.
毕竟，这些是乐理的真正意义所在。
This all can sound very technical and intimidating but
这听起来很有技术含量也很吓人，
I'm not going to be telling you anything that your ears don't already know.
但我不会告诉你任何你没有听说过的东西。
If you listen to music and make music,
如果你听音乐也创造音乐，
even just singing in the shower, you understand it already, at least by sound.
就算只是在洗澡时哼歌，你至少已经通过声音明白了乐理。
All music theory does is label and
所有的乐理都是标签以及
explain what you already are an expert in, as a listener.
解释那些你已经是专家的东西，以一个倾听者的角度。
This course is just the beginning.
这门课程只是一个开端。
From here you could go on to study more advanced music theory, you can compose and
从此你可以开始学习更多先进的音乐理论，你可以作曲和
notate your own melodies and you can add harmonies to tunes you write and hear.
记录你自己的旋律，并且你可以加入旋律到所写或所听到的曲调里。
So let's get started.
那我们开始吧。
[MUSIC]
— 这是一个日常生活场景 四个朋友出去吃午饭